worldsciencefestival.com 2018-12-26

# Privacy Policy | World Science Festival

#### INTRODUCTION

World Science Foundation, d/b/a World Science Festival (referred to collectively in this policy as “WSF,” “we” or “us”) is a 501(c)(3) nonprofit educational organization. Through the website(s) operated at the [worldsciencefestival.com](http://www.worldsciencefestival.com/) (the “Sites”), an annual festival, and other programs, WSF seeks to cultivate a general public informed by science, inspired by wonder, convinced of its value, and prepared to engage with its implications for the future. Sometimes that means obtaining and utilizing, in certain specified ways, personal information from the users of our Sites. This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) applies to the personal information we collect about you through the Sites, regardless of media platform (e.g., computer, smartphone, tablet, etc.). (Please note that World Science Festival may operate other websites, including [worldscienceu.com](http://www.worldscienceu.com/), which have their own separate privacy policies that are not applicable here.) Your privacy is important to us, and this Privacy Policy is designed to make clear our intentions and approach to the collection and use of personal information in connection with our Sites and the choices you have. If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please reach out to us at [info@worldsciencefestival.com](mailto:info@worldsciencefestival.com).

#### CONSENT

By using the Sites, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy, please refrain from using the Sites. Specifically, by submitting any **Personal Information** (as defined below in “Information We Collect & How We Collect It”) to us, you consent and agree that we may collect, use and disclose that **Personal Information** in accordance with this Privacy Policy, and as permitted or required by law. You have the option of refraining from submitting **Personal Information** and reviewing, updating and deleting **Personal Information** you have submitted (by contacting [info@worldsciencefestival.com](mailto:info@worldsciencefestival.com)), and can limit your use of the Sites to those aspects that do not require **Personal Information** if you do not agree with our practices outlined in this Privacy Policy regarding **Personal Information**.

#### INFORMATION WE COLLECT & HOW WE COLLECT IT

For the purposes of operating, improving, and monitoring the user experience on our Sites and World Science Festival operations generally, we collect various information from those using the Sites. This information is broadly of two types: **Personal Information** (meaning information which is personal to you and can be used to identify you, like your name and email address) and **General Information** (meaning information which cannot be used to identify you, like the number of users—but not their names—who have viewed an article).

_**General Information & Cookies**_

You can access content on our Sites and use most feature of our Sites without revealing any **Personal Information**. In these cases we may collect **General Information** including, but not limited to, pages visited, hyperlinks used, type of device used, and time on Sites. Collecting such **General Information** may involve logging the IP address, operating system and browser software used by individual site visitors, and from such information a user’s Internet Service Provider, geographic location, and other data could be inferred, but nothing which can be used to personally identify you. We use this information to understand how to service users of our Sites and improve our Sites and programs. We do this through Google Analytics or other site analysis tools.

We may also use cookies to store and help track information about you to provide you with a customized and personal service (e.g., to keep track of where you are in a particular course and how you have performed on problems).

Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies, and we assume that if you do not disable cookies you consent to use of them by us and by Google Analytics. Most browsers offer easy instructions on setting your browser to reject Google cookies or cookies in general. You may choose to do so at any time, but please note that various personalized functions and benefits of the Sites may not work properly if you reject our cookies.

_**Personal Information**_

We only collect **Personal Information** when you provide it to us directly, for example:

• If you register with us to receive newsletters or other communications from us.  
• If you contact us.  
• If you donate to us.  
• If you purchase tickets to a WSF event via our Sites.  
• If you volunteer.  
• If you add yourself to a waitlist.  
• If you post comments. WSF offers some interactive features on our Sites, such as the ability to comment on content. If you post Personal Information in comments, we may also collect that information.

#### A NOTE ABOUT COMMENT FEATURES ON OUR SITE AND OTHER WSF FORUMS

WSF uses a technology called livefyre to transfer and post on our Sites comments originally posted on the WSF Facebook page or other WSF social media forums, including, without limitation, LinkedIn and Twitter (collectively, “WSF Forums”). Therefore, if you post comments on the WSF Facebook page or other WSF Forums, those comments, and any Personal Information associated with these comments, may appear on our Sites and may be collected by us. (Additional information about livefyre is available at [http://web.livefyre.com](http://web.livefyre.com/).)

#### HOW WE USE PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We use Personal Information we collect on our Sites as described below.

_**Donations**_

WSF collects donations via the Sites through a third party, Patron Manager. When you make an online donation to WSF, you will be directed to the Patron Manager website and you will be asked to provide Personal Information to complete the transaction. At this point, you will be governed by Patron Manager’s privacy policies. Patron Manager will not provide us with your credit card information, but they will give us your name and contact information, which we may use in the future to contact you.

**_Ticket Purchases_**

WSF may sell tickets on our Sites through third party ticketing agents. When you purchase tickets via the Sites, WSF and its third party ticketing agent will request information necessary to process your ticket purchase, which will include Personal Information. In order to complete the purchase, you will be transferred to the ticketing agent’s website and you will be governed by their own independent privacy policy. The ticketing agent will not share your credit card information with us, but they will give us your name and contact information, which we may share with production partners and/or use in the future to contact you.

_**Communication with You**_

**• Sending You Our Newsletter.** If you sign up to receive our newsletter, we will send our newsletter to you periodically via email.  
**• Responding to You.** When you send us an email message or otherwise contact us, we use the Personal Information provided by you to respond. We may also archive this information and/or use it for future communications with you.  
**• Service Messages.** We may use the Personal Information you provide to us to contact you with service messages related to or affecting your use of our Sites, for example, to send you updates about changes in our terms or policies.  
**• Marketing Messages.** We may use the Personal Information you provide to us to send you marketing messages, special offers, promotions, and other information about WSF and its programs, and other products or services that we think may be of interest to you. You may elect to opt-out of these marketing messages at any time by following the opt-out instructions on the communications themselves or by emailing us at [info@worldsciencefestival.com](mailto:info@worldsciencefestival.com).

_**Comments**_

We may republish and reuse your comments with your username or other Personal Information you include in comments and may archive this information for use in future communications with you.

#### DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy or as specifically agreed to by you, WSF will not disclose any **Personal Information** we gather from you on the Sites.

**Third Party Service Providers/Program Partners.** We might share Personal Information with trusted organizations we hire or collaborate with in operating the Sites and programs. For example, if we hire or collaborate with a third party to process our email or handle our help-desk function or work with a partner to help us to develop content and programs, we might share our email list with them. Under all circumstances, however, these third parties would be required to maintain the confidentiality and security of any **Personal Information**.  
**  
Legal and Governmental Authorities/Protection.** To comply with legal requirements that may arise, WSF may share your **Personal Information** if requested to do so by legal or government authorities, or to protect our rights and property under the law. Such uses include, but are not restricted to: responding to court orders or subpoenas, to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims, and to protect our property, including intellectual property and trademarks. In such cases we reserve the right to raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us. We also may share your **Personal Information** when necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal or suspected illegal activities and to protect and defend the rights, property, or safety of WSF and its staff, its properties, our users, or others.

**Disclosure to Acquirers.** WSF may disclose and/or transfer your **Personal Information** to an acquirer, assignee or other successor or potential successor entity in connection with a merger or other reorganization, provided that party agrees to treat your **Personal Information** with protections similar to those under this Privacy Policy.

**Information Posted in Comments.** If you are registered with LiveFyre and logged-in, your LiveFyre user name may appear next to any comments you submit on our Sites. If you post **Personal Information** in comments or other public forums on our Sites or WSF Forums (including, without limitation, the WSF Facebook webpage), that information will be publicly available. If you are concerned about your privacy, we encourage you to use a username that is not personally identifiable and to refrain from posting **Personal Information** in comments or other public forums on our Sites or WSF Forums.

**Other.** To help keep our fundraising costs low and to be able to offer our Sites free of charge, on occasion we may share or rent our mailing list to other nonprofit organizations. You can opt out of this by contacting us at [info@worldsciencefestival.com](mailto:info@worldsciencefestival.com).

**Aggregated Data.** We may share **General Information** , aggregated data or publish information based on aggregated data. However, we will only do so in a way that your personal identity is protected.

#### ACCESS, REVIEW, CHANGING AND DELETING PERSONAL INFORMATION

You may review, edit and delete the Personal Information you have provided to us by contacting us at [info@worldsciencefestival.com](mailto:info@worldsciencefestival.com). Please note, however, that even if you delete your information, there may still residual information about you in our systems, for example in our log files.

#### YOUR RESPONSIBILITIES

You are responsible for ensuring the accuracy of the **Personal Information** you submit to WSF. Submitting inaccurate information, or failing to maintain the accuracy of information that changes (for example, a change of email address) may disrupt your ability to use receive newsletters, may affect the information you receive from us, and may impact our ability to contact you. You can update your **Personal Information** at any time by logging into WSF. and visiting your user account page.

#### EXTERNAL LINKS

WSF may occasionally provide links to sites operated by outside parties (“Third Party Sites”) that we believe may be of interest to you. We do not disclose your **Personal Information** to these Third Party Sites without obtaining your consent. In addition, from our Sites you may be able to interact with social media sites (“Social Media Platforms”), for example, by “liking” us on Facebook. If you choose to click on a link to one of these Third Party Sites or chose to interact with or through a Social Media Platform, your activities are not governed by this Privacy Policy and will be governed by the privacy policy on that Third Party Site or Social Media Platform. Please review their privacy policies and terms of service before disclosing any Personal Information there. WSF does not review and expressly does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy practices of these Third Party Sites and Social Media Platforms.

We may also maintain a WSF page on Facebook or other WSF Forum (as defined in “A Note about Comment Features on Our Sites and WSF Forums” above). Those pages and your interaction with them are governed by the privacy policies of Facebook or other relevant WSF Forum site and not our Privacy Policy. We may, however, use livefyre to automatically or selectively post comments from WSF Forums on our Sites. As with other Third Party Sites, WSF expressly does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy practices of WSF Forums, although we may have a presence on them.

#### SECURITY

World Science Festival is committed to protecting the security of our users’ Personal Information. To that end, WSF uses industry standard security practices to keep your **Personal Information** private, and to protect it from disclosure to or access by third parties. We will not share it with third parties, except as directed by you or as otherwise specified in this Privacy Policy. Please note, however, that we do not and cannot guarantee the security of Personal Information, and there is some risk that an unauthorized third party may find a way to circumvent our security systems, or that transmission of your information over the Internet will be intercepted.

#### CHANGING OUR PRIVACY POLICY

We review our privacy practices from time to time, and these practices are subject to changes and updates, which will be effective immediately. We will notify you of any material change to this Privacy Policy by posting a notice on our homepage(s) for a reasonable period of time following such update, by reflecting the change on this Privacy Policy page, and by updating the Effective Date located at the bottom of this page. To ensure familiarity with the current version of our Privacy Policy, return to this page periodically. We will not apply any changes retroactively.

#### PROTECTING CHILDREN’S PRIVACY

WSF strongly believes in protecting the privacy of children. We do not knowingly collect or maintain any **Personal Information** on our Sites from persons under 13 years of age, and no part of our Sites are directed to persons under 13 years of age. Upon learning of the existence of **Personal Information** concerning persons less than 13 years of age that has been collected on our Sites without verified parental consent, we will take appropriate steps to delete it. If you are at least 13, but not yet 18 years of age, you must obtain the permission of a parent or legal guardian before using any of the interactive features of our Sites, such as subscribing to our newsletter, commenting, donating or purchasing tickets.

#### GOVERNING LAW; INTERNATIONAL USERS

This Privacy Policy shall be governed by the laws of the State of New York (United States), excluding any laws that might direct the application of the laws of another jurisdiction. Note that we may store and process **Personal Information** on servers or on a cloud located in the United States or elsewhere. The data protection laws of New York and the United States generally may not be as comprehensive or the same as those in the country where you are located. By using our Sites, you agree and consent that your **Personal Information** may be transferred to our facilities in the United States or elsewhere and those of the third parties with whom we share it as described in this Privacy Policy.

#### QUESTIONS OR CONCERNS

If you have any trouble logging in, or have any privacy-related questions or unresolved problems, contact us via [info@worldsciencefestival.com](mailto:info@worldsciencefestival.com).

_Effective as of November 20, 2014_
